# **Xiaoxia Cheng**

Montreal, QC, Canada **(514) 586-8226** 

jenniferyao1996@hotmail.COM

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/cheng-jennifer-xiaoxia/

Portfolio: <u>jennifer-portfolio-cxxyao2.vercel.app</u>

## **Apply for positions**

Front-End Software Engineer, Full Stack developer, technical support engineer, QA engineer

## **Summary**

Rich experience in developing, implementing and maintaining complex software projects. Now focus on frontend frameworks including Angular 6+, React, Next.js. Use Node.js and c# in backend development as needed.

Solid knowledge of OOP, design patterns, databases(Oracle, Mysql, Sql server, MongoDB), RESTful api, GraphQL. Experience in automation tests using Karma, jasmine, jest and cypress.

Experience in Git-based Microsoft development environment Azure Devops and agile development.

A good team worker, technical communicator, problem-solver, self-driven, always professional and enthusiastic.

#### Skills

- 10 Years: .net, Oracle, MS Sql Server
- 4 Years: Typescript, Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML5, Bootstrap, Github
- 3 Years:React, Mysql, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Redux, Angular 6+, NGXS, Mongo, Node.js
- 1 Year+: NGXS, Redux, Cypress, jest, Karma, Firestore, Tailwind CSS, c#, Next.js, JQuery
- Expertise in Asset Management, CRM and MES.
- Strong understanding of SEO, SOLID code principles. Prioritize usability and accessibility

# **Experience**

Nov 2021 - July 2023

#### ADNM.NET, Montreal, Canada - Frontend developer

- Tech stack: Angular 12+, Material UI, React, Bootstrap CSS, NGXS, Cypress, Karma, c#
- Helped the team deliver on time via task breakdown, scope management and QA.
- Troubleshooted bugs or flaws mainly related to asynchronous processing and responsive UI.
- Optimized overall website performance collaborating with backend developers.
- Contributed to automatic API test, unit test, system test, technical documentation
- Developed new user-specific features using Typescript, SCSS, Angular, React etc.

### A learner and freelancer

- Took a career break to take care of my family. Took full-time french courses
- Took high quality online courses to systematically learn Javascript and related frontend frameworks
- Worked as a volunteer to develop an online article repository using PHP, laravel, Mysql ,React and Storybook, AJAX, JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.

Oct 2014- July 2018

#### Yonyou company, Shanghai - Technical Consultant

- Tech Stack: Java, Html, MS project, Geolocation Management, Office 365
- Participated in creating and executing ERP system implement plans
- Worked closely with development team and end-users to ensure deliver right CRM product
- Trained users and new employees in best practice to utilize ERP to its fullest capacity
- Helped accountants adapt to financial policy changes by configuring reports on BI platform
- Helped salespersons increase lead, accelerate orders, manage accounts receivable and commission

Oct 2001 - Sep 2014

#### CITS company, Shanghai - Senior Software Engineer

- Tech stack: Java, .net, Oracle, MS Sql server
- Delivered high quality custom softwares for users mainly in production industries. Helped users to optimize production plans and schedules, manage lead time, timely report production cost data, manage e-commerce orders and stock, etc.
- Implemented applications in factories and offer on-going support
- Contributed document control. Wrote test cases from Unit Test to E2E test.

Sep 1999 - July 2001

#### Finet.hk company, Shenzhen, China - Database Developer

Defined database specifications. Wrote queries. Replicated, backuped, tuned database.

Aug 1996 - July 1999

#### Gezhouba Group, Yichang, China- Junior Software Engineer

 Participated in developing a custom application to manage hydroelectricity project cost using VB and SqlServer

### Education

Sep 1992 - July 1996

Nankai university, Tianjin - Bachelor of computer and information

## Languages

English, French, Japanese, Mandarin